<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fog Computing on Eugene Siow</title>
    <link>http://eugenesiow.com/tags/fog-computing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Fog Computing on Eugene Siow</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://eugenesiow.com/tags/fog-computing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Demystifying the Fog: Rapid and Interoperable Computing for the Internet of Things</title>
      <link>http://eugenesiow.com/talks/oxford_2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://eugenesiow.com/talks/oxford_2017/</guid>
      <description>Abstract This talk presented various papers and work done on the Map-Match-Operate abstraction for databases and streams to make efficient and interoperable query processing on Fog Computing devices possible, personal IoT repositories, the Eywa fog computing infrastructure, the Social Web of Things and TritanDB.
Slides   Event Information The IoT Observatory aims to address research challenges related to sharing IoT datasets on a large distributed scale to support innovation in a way that will not compromise privacy and security.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ewya: An Interoperable Fog Computing Infrastructure with RDF Stream Processing</title>
      <link>http://eugenesiow.com/publications/eywa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://eugenesiow.com/publications/eywa/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Fog computing is an emerging technology for the Internet of Things (IoT) that aims to support processing on resource-constrained distributed nodes in between the sensors and actuators on the ground and compute clusters in the cloud. Fog Computing benefits from low latency, location awareness, mobility, wide-spread deployment and geographical distribution at the edge of the network. However, there is a need to investigate, optimise for and measure the performance, scalability and interoperability of resource-constrained Fog nodes running real-time applications and queries on streaming IoT data before we can realise these benefits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Biological Internet: Building Eywa</title>
      <link>http://eugenesiow.com/talks/shenzhen_2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://eugenesiow.com/talks/shenzhen_2017/</guid>
      <description>Abstract In James Cameron&amp;rsquo;s Avatar, Eywa is the guiding force and deity of the world, Pandora. Eywa is like a huge biological internet; the trees being computer servers that store information and sensors being neural-connected flora and fauna making up the planets ecosystem. We study how this science fiction construct can be brought to life by our research on building the Social Web of Things with fog computing for decentralisation and workload distribution, Linked Data for interoperability and fast stream processing with storage and processing optimisations on lightweight computers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Patching Mr Robot: Mitigating IoT-related Cyber-social Disasters By Getting Fog Computing to Work</title>
      <link>http://eugenesiow.com/talks/kaist_2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://eugenesiow.com/talks/kaist_2016/</guid>
      <description>Slides   Event Information It was back to the Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology (KAIST) in Daejeon, South Korea for the 3rd International Disaster Management Workshop. As per the last few times, there were some really excellent speakers from a diverse range of studies. These included presentations on Bio Engineering, Law, Computer Science, Social Media Analytics, Civil Engineering and Food Nutrition.
I presented some of my work on Fog Computing, optimising Linked Data for Lightweight Computers and Personal IoT Repositories.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>