<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>IoT on Eugene Siow</title>
    <link>http://eugenesiow.com/tags/iot/</link>
    <description>Recent content in IoT on Eugene Siow</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://eugenesiow.com/tags/iot/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Analytics for the Internet of Things: A Survey</title>
      <link>http://eugenesiow.com/publications/analytics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://eugenesiow.com/publications/analytics/</guid>
      <description>Abstract The Internet of Things (IoT) envisions a world-wide, interconnected network of smart physical entities. These physical entities generate a large amount of data in operation, and as the IoT gains momentum in terms of deployment, the combined scale of those data seems destined to continue to grow. Increasingly, applications for the IoT involve analytics. Data analytics is the process of deriving knowledge from data, generating value like actionable insights from them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Efficient Querying for Analytics on Internet of Things Databases and Streams</title>
      <link>http://eugenesiow.com/talks/defence_2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://eugenesiow.com/talks/defence_2017/</guid>
      <description>Abstract This thesis is concerned with the development of efficient methods for managing contextualised time-series data and event streams produced by the Internet of Things (IoT) so that both historical and real-time information can be utilised to generate value within analytical applications.
From a database systems perspective, two conflicting challenges motivate this research, interoperability and performance. IoT applications integrating streams of time-series data from heterogeneous IoT agents require a level of semantic interoperability.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demystifying the Fog: Rapid and Interoperable Computing for the Internet of Things</title>
      <link>http://eugenesiow.com/talks/oxford_2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://eugenesiow.com/talks/oxford_2017/</guid>
      <description>Abstract This talk presented various papers and work done on the Map-Match-Operate abstraction for databases and streams to make efficient and interoperable query processing on Fog Computing devices possible, personal IoT repositories, the Eywa fog computing infrastructure, the Social Web of Things and TritanDB.
Slides Event Information The IoT Observatory aims to address research challenges related to sharing IoT datasets on a large distributed scale to support innovation in a way that will not compromise privacy and security.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ewya: An Interoperable Fog Computing Infrastructure with RDF Stream Processing</title>
      <link>http://eugenesiow.com/publications/eywa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://eugenesiow.com/publications/eywa/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Fog computing is an emerging technology for the Internet of Things (IoT) that aims to support processing on resource-constrained distributed nodes in between the sensors and actuators on the ground and compute clusters in the cloud. Fog Computing benefits from low latency, location awareness, mobility, wide-spread deployment and geographical distribution at the edge of the network. However, there is a need to investigate, optimise for and measure the performance, scalability and interoperability of resource-constrained Fog nodes running real-time applications and queries on streaming IoT data before we can realise these benefits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Biological Internet: Building Eywa</title>
      <link>http://eugenesiow.com/talks/shenzhen_2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://eugenesiow.com/talks/shenzhen_2017/</guid>
      <description>Abstract In James Cameron&amp;rsquo;s Avatar, Eywa is the guiding force and deity of the world, Pandora. Eywa is like a huge biological internet; the trees being computer servers that store information and sensors being neural-connected flora and fauna making up the planets ecosystem. We study how this science fiction construct can be brought to life by our research on building the Social Web of Things with fog computing for decentralisation and workload distribution, Linked Data for interoperability and fast stream processing with storage and processing optimisations on lightweight computers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Patching Mr Robot: Mitigating IoT-related Cyber-social Disasters By Getting Fog Computing to Work</title>
      <link>http://eugenesiow.com/talks/kaist_2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://eugenesiow.com/talks/kaist_2016/</guid>
      <description>Slides Event Information It was back to the Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology (KAIST) in Daejeon, South Korea for the 3rd International Disaster Management Workshop. As per the last few times, there were some really excellent speakers from a diverse range of studies. These included presentations on Bio Engineering, Law, Computer Science, Social Media Analytics, Civil Engineering and Food Nutrition.
I presented some of my work on Fog Computing, optimising Linked Data for Lightweight Computers and Personal IoT Repositories.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PIOTRe: Personal Internet of Things Repository</title>
      <link>http://eugenesiow.com/publications/piotre/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://eugenesiow.com/publications/piotre/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Resource-constrained Internet of Things (IoT) devices like Raspberry Pis&amp;rsquo;, with specific performance optimisation, can serve as interoperable personal Linked Data repositories for IoT applications. In this demo paper we describe PIOTRe, a personal datastore that utilises our sparql2sql query translation technology on Pis&amp;rsquo; to process, store and publish IoT time-series historical data and streams. We demonstrate with PIOTRe in a smart home scenario: a real-time dashboard that utilises RDF stream processing, a set of descriptive analytics visualisations on historical data, a framework for registering stream queries within a local network and a means of sharing metadata globally with HyperCat and Web Observatories.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SPARQL-to-SQL on Internet of Things Databases and Streams</title>
      <link>http://eugenesiow.com/publications/sparql2sql/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://eugenesiow.com/publications/sparql2sql/</guid>
      <description>Abstract To realise a semantic Web of Things, the challenge of achieving efficient Resource Description Format (RDF) storage and SPARQL query performance on Internet of Things (IoT) devices with limited resources has to be addressed. State-of-the-art SPARQL-to-SQL engines have been shown to outperform RDF stores on some benchmarks. In this paper, we describe an optimisation to the SPARQL-to-SQL approach, based on a study of time-series IoT data structures, that employs metadata abstraction and efficient translation by reusing existing SPARQL engines to produce Linked Data ‘just-in-time’.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interoperable &amp; Efficient: Linked Data for the Internet of Things</title>
      <link>http://eugenesiow.com/publications/iot_linked_data/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://eugenesiow.com/publications/iot_linked_data/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Two requirements to utilise the large source of time-series sensor data from the Internet of Things are interoperability and efficient access. We present a Linked Data solution that increases interoperability through the use and referencing of common identifiers and ontologies for integration. From our study of the shape of Internet of Things data, we show how we can improve access within the resource constraints of Lightweight Computers, compact machines deployed in close proximity to sensors, by storing time-series data succinctly as rows and producing Linked Data ‘just-in-time’.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Efficient and Interoperable: Linked Data for the Internet of Things</title>
      <link>http://eugenesiow.com/talks/rda_plenary_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://eugenesiow.com/talks/rda_plenary_7/</guid>
      <description>Poster Abstract Internet of Things (IoT) applications and services need data, which is collected from distributed and heterogeneous sensors, to be aggregated, integrated and interpreted in the context of other sources of information. Linked Data can facilitate this through the use of common identifiers, ontologies and self-describing semantics. However, storing sensor data as Linked Data is inefficient in terms of storage and query performance which is further exacerbated by the resource constraints of compact devices &amp;amp; hubs that are deployed in close proximity to sensors to perform this integration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rapid Response Linked Data</title>
      <link>http://eugenesiow.com/talks/kaist_2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://eugenesiow.com/talks/kaist_2015/</guid>
      <description>Slides Event Information I presented some of my work at the International Workshop of Social Machines for Disaster Management at the Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology (KAIST) in Daejeon, Korea. KAIST is truly the MIT of South Korea! I had a great time interacting with the brilliant researchers there - social scientists, medical doctors, computer scientists and policy studies academics!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>