<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks on Eugene Siow</title>
    <link>http://eugenesiow.com/talks/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Talks on Eugene Siow</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://eugenesiow.com/talks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Efficient Querying for Analytics on Internet of Things Databases and Streams</title>
      <link>http://eugenesiow.com/talks/defence_2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://eugenesiow.com/talks/defence_2017/</guid>
      <description>Abstract This thesis is concerned with the development of efficient methods for managing contextualised time-series data and event streams produced by the Internet of Things (IoT) so that both historical and real-time information can be utilised to generate value within analytical applications.
From a database systems perspective, two conflicting challenges motivate this research, interoperability and performance. IoT applications integrating streams of time-series data from heterogeneous IoT agents require a level of semantic interoperability.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demystifying the Fog: Rapid and Interoperable Computing for the Internet of Things</title>
      <link>http://eugenesiow.com/talks/oxford_2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://eugenesiow.com/talks/oxford_2017/</guid>
      <description>Abstract This talk presented various papers and work done on the Map-Match-Operate abstraction for databases and streams to make efficient and interoperable query processing on Fog Computing devices possible, personal IoT repositories, the Eywa fog computing infrastructure, the Social Web of Things and TritanDB.
Slides   Event Information The IoT Observatory aims to address research challenges related to sharing IoT datasets on a large distributed scale to support innovation in a way that will not compromise privacy and security.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web Observatory: Connecting Data, Apps and Analytics</title>
      <link>http://eugenesiow.com/talks/digital_day_2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://eugenesiow.com/talks/digital_day_2017/</guid>
      <description>Poster Abstract The Web Observatory is a system that locates and makes visible your metadata or, if you choose, your actual data, apps and projects from around the world. It has common technical standards, safe guards, collection and analysis tools, to allow us to observe the web and use the intelligence it holds in new and exciting ways.
Researchers and developers from around the world are contributing their metadata, datasets,apps and tools to existing web observatories.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Biological Internet: Building Eywa</title>
      <link>http://eugenesiow.com/talks/shenzhen_2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://eugenesiow.com/talks/shenzhen_2017/</guid>
      <description>Abstract In James Cameron&amp;rsquo;s Avatar, Eywa is the guiding force and deity of the world, Pandora. Eywa is like a huge biological internet; the trees being computer servers that store information and sensors being neural-connected flora and fauna making up the planets ecosystem. We study how this science fiction construct can be brought to life by our research on building the Social Web of Things with fog computing for decentralisation and workload distribution, Linked Data for interoperability and fast stream processing with storage and processing optimisations on lightweight computers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Patching Mr Robot: Mitigating IoT-related Cyber-social Disasters By Getting Fog Computing to Work</title>
      <link>http://eugenesiow.com/talks/kaist_2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://eugenesiow.com/talks/kaist_2016/</guid>
      <description>Slides   Event Information It was back to the Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology (KAIST) in Daejeon, South Korea for the 3rd International Disaster Management Workshop. As per the last few times, there were some really excellent speakers from a diverse range of studies. These included presentations on Bio Engineering, Law, Computer Science, Social Media Analytics, Civil Engineering and Food Nutrition.
I presented some of my work on Fog Computing, optimising Linked Data for Lightweight Computers and Personal IoT Repositories.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Efficient and Interoperable: Linked Data for the Internet of Things</title>
      <link>http://eugenesiow.com/talks/rda_plenary_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://eugenesiow.com/talks/rda_plenary_7/</guid>
      <description>Poster Abstract Internet of Things (IoT) applications and services need data, which is collected from distributed and heterogeneous sensors, to be aggregated, integrated and interpreted in the context of other sources of information. Linked Data can facilitate this through the use of common identifiers, ontologies and self-describing semantics. However, storing sensor data as Linked Data is inefficient in terms of storage and query performance which is further exacerbated by the resource constraints of compact devices &amp;amp; hubs that are deployed in close proximity to sensors to perform this integration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rapid Response Linked Data</title>
      <link>http://eugenesiow.com/talks/kaist_2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://eugenesiow.com/talks/kaist_2015/</guid>
      <description>Slides   Event Information I presented some of my work at the International Workshop of Social Machines for Disaster Management at the Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology (KAIST) in Daejeon, Korea. KAIST is truly the MIT of South Korea! I had a great time interacting with the brilliant researchers there - social scientists, medical doctors, computer scientists and policy studies academics!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>