<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Social Web on Eugene Siow</title>
    <link>http://eugenesiow.com/tags/social-web/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Social Web on Eugene Siow</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://eugenesiow.com/tags/social-web/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Demystifying the Fog: Rapid and Interoperable Computing for the Internet of Things</title>
      <link>http://eugenesiow.com/talks/oxford_2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://eugenesiow.com/talks/oxford_2017/</guid>
      <description>Abstract This talk presented various papers and work done on the Map-Match-Operate abstraction for databases and streams to make efficient and interoperable query processing on Fog Computing devices possible, personal IoT repositories, the Eywa fog computing infrastructure, the Social Web of Things and TritanDB.
Slides   Event Information The IoT Observatory aims to address research challenges related to sharing IoT datasets on a large distributed scale to support innovation in a way that will not compromise privacy and security.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Biological Internet: Building Eywa</title>
      <link>http://eugenesiow.com/talks/shenzhen_2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://eugenesiow.com/talks/shenzhen_2017/</guid>
      <description>Abstract In James Cameron&amp;rsquo;s Avatar, Eywa is the guiding force and deity of the world, Pandora. Eywa is like a huge biological internet; the trees being computer servers that store information and sensors being neural-connected flora and fauna making up the planets ecosystem. We study how this science fiction construct can be brought to life by our research on building the Social Web of Things with fog computing for decentralisation and workload distribution, Linked Data for interoperability and fast stream processing with storage and processing optimisations on lightweight computers.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>