<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rsp on Eugene Siow</title>
    <link>http://eugenesiow.com/tags/rsp/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Rsp on Eugene Siow</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://eugenesiow.com/tags/rsp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Efficient Querying for Analytics on Internet of Things Databases and Streams</title>
      <link>http://eugenesiow.com/talks/defence_2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://eugenesiow.com/talks/defence_2017/</guid>
      <description>Abstract This thesis is concerned with the development of efficient methods for managing contextualised time-series data and event streams produced by the Internet of Things (IoT) so that both historical and real-time information can be utilised to generate value within analytical applications.
From a database systems perspective, two conflicting challenges motivate this research, interoperability and performance. IoT applications integrating streams of time-series data from heterogeneous IoT agents require a level of semantic interoperability.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demystifying the Fog: Rapid and Interoperable Computing for the Internet of Things</title>
      <link>http://eugenesiow.com/talks/oxford_2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://eugenesiow.com/talks/oxford_2017/</guid>
      <description>Abstract This talk presented various papers and work done on the Map-Match-Operate abstraction for databases and streams to make efficient and interoperable query processing on Fog Computing devices possible, personal IoT repositories, the Eywa fog computing infrastructure, the Social Web of Things and TritanDB.
Slides   Event Information The IoT Observatory aims to address research challenges related to sharing IoT datasets on a large distributed scale to support innovation in a way that will not compromise privacy and security.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ewya: An Interoperable Fog Computing Infrastructure with RDF Stream Processing</title>
      <link>http://eugenesiow.com/publications/eywa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://eugenesiow.com/publications/eywa/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Fog computing is an emerging technology for the Internet of Things (IoT) that aims to support processing on resource-constrained distributed nodes in between the sensors and actuators on the ground and compute clusters in the cloud. Fog Computing benefits from low latency, location awareness, mobility, wide-spread deployment and geographical distribution at the edge of the network. However, there is a need to investigate, optimise for and measure the performance, scalability and interoperability of resource-constrained Fog nodes running real-time applications and queries on streaming IoT data before we can realise these benefits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Biological Internet: Building Eywa</title>
      <link>http://eugenesiow.com/talks/shenzhen_2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://eugenesiow.com/talks/shenzhen_2017/</guid>
      <description>Abstract In James Cameron&amp;rsquo;s Avatar, Eywa is the guiding force and deity of the world, Pandora. Eywa is like a huge biological internet; the trees being computer servers that store information and sensors being neural-connected flora and fauna making up the planets ecosystem. We study how this science fiction construct can be brought to life by our research on building the Social Web of Things with fog computing for decentralisation and workload distribution, Linked Data for interoperability and fast stream processing with storage and processing optimisations on lightweight computers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PIOTRe: Personal Internet of Things Repository</title>
      <link>http://eugenesiow.com/publications/piotre/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://eugenesiow.com/publications/piotre/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Resource-constrained Internet of Things (IoT) devices like Raspberry Pis&amp;rsquo;, with specific performance optimisation, can serve as interoperable personal Linked Data repositories for IoT applications. In this demo paper we describe PIOTRe, a personal datastore that utilises our sparql2sql query translation technology on Pis&amp;rsquo; to process, store and publish IoT time-series historical data and streams. We demonstrate with PIOTRe in a smart home scenario: a real-time dashboard that utilises RDF stream processing, a set of descriptive analytics visualisations on historical data, a framework for registering stream queries within a local network and a means of sharing metadata globally with HyperCat and Web Observatories.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SPARQL-to-SQL on Internet of Things Databases and Streams</title>
      <link>http://eugenesiow.com/publications/sparql2sql/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://eugenesiow.com/publications/sparql2sql/</guid>
      <description>Abstract To realise a semantic Web of Things, the challenge of achieving efficient Resource Description Format (RDF) storage and SPARQL query performance on Internet of Things (IoT) devices with limited resources has to be addressed. State-of-the-art SPARQL-to-SQL engines have been shown to outperform RDF stores on some benchmarks. In this paper, we describe an optimisation to the SPARQL-to-SQL approach, based on a study of time-series IoT data structures, that employs metadata abstraction and efficient translation by reusing existing SPARQL engines to produce Linked Data ‘just-in-time’.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>