<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Publications on Eugene Siow</title>
    <link>http://eugenesiow.com/publications/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Publications on Eugene Siow</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://eugenesiow.com/publications/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Analytics for the Internet of Things: A Survey</title>
      <link>http://eugenesiow.com/publications/analytics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://eugenesiow.com/publications/analytics/</guid>
      <description>Abstract The Internet of Things (IoT) envisions a world-wide, interconnected network of smart physical entities. These physical entities generate a large amount of data in operation, and as the IoT gains momentum in terms of deployment, the combined scale of those data seems destined to continue to grow. Increasingly, applications for the IoT involve analytics. Data analytics is the process of deriving knowledge from data, generating value like actionable insights from them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ewya: An Interoperable Fog Computing Infrastructure with RDF Stream Processing</title>
      <link>http://eugenesiow.com/publications/eywa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://eugenesiow.com/publications/eywa/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Fog computing is an emerging technology for the Internet of Things (IoT) that aims to support processing on resource-constrained distributed nodes in between the sensors and actuators on the ground and compute clusters in the cloud. Fog Computing benefits from low latency, location awareness, mobility, wide-spread deployment and geographical distribution at the edge of the network. However, there is a need to investigate, optimise for and measure the performance, scalability and interoperability of resource-constrained Fog nodes running real-time applications and queries on streaming IoT data before we can realise these benefits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sharing Databases on the Web with Porter Proxy</title>
      <link>http://eugenesiow.com/publications/porter_proxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://eugenesiow.com/publications/porter_proxy/</guid>
      <description>Abstract With large number of datasets now available through the Web, data-sharing ecosystems such as the Web Observatory have emerged. The Web Observatory provides an active decentralised ecosystem for datasets and applications based on a number Web Observatory sites, each of which can run in a different administrative domain. On a Web Observatory site users can publish and securely access datasets across domains via a harmonised API and reverse proxies for access control.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PIOTRe: Personal Internet of Things Repository</title>
      <link>http://eugenesiow.com/publications/piotre/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://eugenesiow.com/publications/piotre/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Resource-constrained Internet of Things (IoT) devices like Raspberry Pis&amp;rsquo;, with specific performance optimisation, can serve as interoperable personal Linked Data repositories for IoT applications. In this demo paper we describe PIOTRe, a personal datastore that utilises our sparql2sql query translation technology on Pis&amp;rsquo; to process, store and publish IoT time-series historical data and streams. We demonstrate with PIOTRe in a smart home scenario: a real-time dashboard that utilises RDF stream processing, a set of descriptive analytics visualisations on historical data, a framework for registering stream queries within a local network and a means of sharing metadata globally with HyperCat and Web Observatories.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SPARQL-to-SQL on Internet of Things Databases and Streams</title>
      <link>http://eugenesiow.com/publications/sparql2sql/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://eugenesiow.com/publications/sparql2sql/</guid>
      <description>Abstract To realise a semantic Web of Things, the challenge of achieving efficient Resource Description Format (RDF) storage and SPARQL query performance on Internet of Things (IoT) devices with limited resources has to be addressed. State-of-the-art SPARQL-to-SQL engines have been shown to outperform RDF stores on some benchmarks. In this paper, we describe an optimisation to the SPARQL-to-SQL approach, based on a study of time-series IoT data structures, that employs metadata abstraction and efficient translation by reusing existing SPARQL engines to produce Linked Data ‘just-in-time’.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interoperable &amp; Efficient: Linked Data for the Internet of Things</title>
      <link>http://eugenesiow.com/publications/iot_linked_data/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://eugenesiow.com/publications/iot_linked_data/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Two requirements to utilise the large source of time-series sensor data from the Internet of Things are interoperability and efficient access. We present a Linked Data solution that increases interoperability through the use and referencing of common identifiers and ontologies for integration. From our study of the shape of Internet of Things data, we show how we can improve access within the resource constraints of Lightweight Computers, compact machines deployed in close proximity to sensors, by storing time-series data succinctly as rows and producing Linked Data ‘just-in-time’.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cross-IoT Study of the Characteristics of IoT Schemata and Data Streams</title>
      <link>http://eugenesiow.com/publications/cross_iot/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://eugenesiow.com/publications/cross_iot/</guid>
      <description>A broad cross-IoT study of the characteristics of Things schemata and data streams. The aim of the study is to determine the flatness, width, types of attribute values and periodicity of current IoT data streams from various domains and use cases.
There are individual README.md files describing each of the datasets and the files within the dataset in more detail.
Studies:  SparkFun: 614 schemata of devices in Jan 2016 : Folder /sparkfun/ ThingSpeak: 9033 schemata of devices in July 2017 : Folder /ThingSpeak/ Array of Things: 9033 schemata of devices in July 2017 : Folder /array_of_things/ OpenEnergyMonitor EmonCMS: 9033 schemata of devices in July 2017 : Folder /EmonCms/ Open Humans: HealthKit, Fitbit, RunKeeper and Move schemata in July/August 2017 : Folder /OpenHumans/  Date of data collection Jan 2016 to August 2017</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dweet.io IoT device schema</title>
      <link>http://eugenesiow.com/publications/dweetio/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://eugenesiow.com/publications/dweetio/</guid>
      <description>A collection of IoT schemata to determine the characteristics of IoT data. The focus was on whether IoT data was complex or flat, wide or narrow, numerical or non-numerical and even or unevenly spaced.
There were 22,662 schemata collected in Jan2016 of which 1,541 are empty and 9,561 are non-IoT schemata (dweet.zip). Each schema is a .json file and they are classified into folders (complex, empty, flat).
Additional collected content (available in Apr 2017) of dweets is in another file called dweet_content.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Facilitating data-driven innovation using VOICE observatory infrastructure</title>
      <link>http://eugenesiow.com/publications/vo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://eugenesiow.com/publications/vo/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Data is the new capital of the global economy and data analysis can increase efficiency and reduce costs for innovation. Finding and accessing both public and private data is essential to exploiting this data capital. In this paper we describe a platform, VOICE Observatory (VO), that provides an infrastructure and analytical resources to facilitate data-driven innovation. The VO curates a catalogue of analytical resources and provides secure access to them.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>